RG 182, State Board of Accountancy
Connecticut State Library
State Board of Accountancy records
1907-2007
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. State Board of Accountancy
26 cubic feet
The Board of Accountancy protects the users of services rendered by Connecticut licensed accountants by regulating the authorized practice of public accountancy by certified public accountants (CPA) and public accountants as well as the unauthorized practice of public accountancy by unlicensed individuals and firms.
RG182
2006-005 and 2008-036
Historical Note
The State Board of Accountancy was established in 1907 per Public Acts, Chpt. 202. It was terminated in 1979 by P.A. 77-614, s. 573(d)(6), reestablished as a component of the Dept. of Consumer Protection, per P.A. 77-614, s. 209. It was transferred to the Office of the Secretaty of the State in 1985 per P.A. 85-504. It was terminated in 1992 by P.A. 92-212 and reestablished as a separate entity. P.A. 11-48 placed the State Board of Accountancy within the Office of the Secretary of the State effective July 1, 2011.
See also the brief description of the.
Scope and Contents
Minutes, 1907-2007; Attendance record, 1981-1986; Public Accountants program files including intentions to practice and authority to practice, 1955-1958. Both intentions to practice and authority to practice contain the application but the latter includes the letter granting such authority. An applicant's file will be in one or the other of these.
Arrangement
Minutes are arranged chronologically in volumes.
Public Accountants Program files are arranged in two subseries, intentions to practice and authority to practice. Files are alphabetical within these subseries.
Index Terms
Organizations:
Connecticut. State Board of Accountancy
Subjects:
Connecticut. State Board of Accountancy -- Records and correspondence; Accountants -- Certification -- Connecticut
Document Types:
Application forms; Correspondence; Minutes
Restrictions on Access
These records are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
Attendance record, 1981-1986, is restricted because the sheet attached to the inside front cover contains social security numbers. Contact State Archives staff for assistance.
See the policy.
Acquisition Information
Accession 2006-005 was transferred to the Connecticut State Library on September 22, 2005.
Accession 2008-036 was transferred to the Connecticut State Library on April 1, 2008.
Container List
- Series 1. Minutes, 1907-2007; 2008-036
  Volumes 16-28 were transferred with no volume number assigned. Numbering was continued by State Archives staff.
  - 1907 June 13 - 1932 November 17 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1933 January 17 - 1949 August 1 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1949 November 16 - 1957 July 9 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1957 August 28 - 1960 July 14 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1960 July 26 - 1964 June 16 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 1966 July 13 - 1973 February 28 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 1973 March 30 - 1977 May 24 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 1977 June 6 - 1980 May 19 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 1980 June 11 - 1982 December 8 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - 1983 January 12 - 1986 February 12 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 1986 March 12 - 1989 July 11 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - 1989 July 18 - 1991 February 19 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - 1991 March 16 - 1992 April 7 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - 1992 April 28 - November 24 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - 1993 January 5 - September 14 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - 1993 October 19 - 1994 August 2 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - 1994 September 13 - 1996 January 17 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - 1996 February - 1997 January (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - 1997 February - 1998 March (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - 1998 April - 1999 July (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - 1999 August - 2000 September (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - 2000 October - 2001 March (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - 2001 April - 2002 March (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - 2002 April - 2003 March (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - 2003 April - 2004 May (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - 2004 June - 2005 July (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - 2005 August - 2006 December (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - 2007 January - December (Box 4, Folder 28)
- Series 2. Attendance Record, 1981-1986; 2008-036
  - 1981-1986 (Box Item 5)
    RESTRICTED
- Series 3. Public Accountants Program Files, 1955-1958; 2005-006
  - Intentions to Practice
    - Ableski - Carlton (Box 1)
    - Case - Fanelli (Box 2)
    - Fappiano - Hoffman (Box 3)
    - Hogan - Lyons (Box 4)
    - Macary - Peters (Box 5)
    - Petrillo - Stuselitas (Box 6)
    - Stuchy - Zulkoski (Box 7)
  - Authority to Practice
    - Abbott - Bloom, J. (Box 8)
    - Bloom, L. - Clyne (Box 9)
    - Cobb - Dolan, V. (Box 10)
    - Dolan, W. - Frost (Box 11)
    - Fulco - Henault (Box 12)
    - Hendel - Keeler (Box 13)
    - Keeley - Luft (Box 14)
    - Lukesiewicz - Mulville (Box 15)
    - Murenia - Plant (Box 16)
    - Plumb - Ryle (Box 17)
    - Sabo - Staiano (Box 18)
    - Stankiewicz - Wheeler (Box 19)
    - Whinston - Zoppo (Box 20)
  - Log book, 1955-1958 (Box 21)
  - Card file (Box 21-22)